{"tossups": [{"question": "This thinker\u2019s work<em> The Sand Reckoner</em> is the most comprehensive surviving source for Aristarchus\u2019heliocentric theory. He was the first to develop formulas for the volume and surface area of a sphere and invented a namesake \u201cscrew\u201d used for raising water, but his \u201cdeath ray\u201d did not actually sink a fleet attacking his home, Syracuse. For ten points, name this scientist who supposedly ran through the streets shouting \u201cEureka!\u201d after discovering the principle of buoyancy.", "answer": "<b> Archimedes</b> of Syracuse", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Misc Science"}, {}, {"question": "In this battle, an I-168 sank the<em> USS Hammann</em>, which was picking up survivors from a ship captained by Elliot Buckmaster; that ship lagged behind the Enterprise and Hornet. The<em> USS Yorktown</em> was lost, but four Japanese carriers were destroyed in, for ten points, what decisive American victory, the turning point of the Pacific theater of World War II?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Midway</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This organization controlled the Saarland for 15 years before a referendum supported German rule. It did nothing in response to the Mukden incident, after which Japan withdrew from this organization. The U.S. Senate\u2019s refusal to sign the Treaty of Versailles meant that the U.S. never joined this organization. For ten points, name this international body that was unable to prevent World War II and was replaced by the United Nations.", "answer": "<b> League of Nations</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This composer popularized a percussion-heavy style music inspired by Janissary bands with an opera in which Belmonte rescues Konstanze from Pasha Selim\u2019s harem. He included heavy Masonic symbolism in an opera in which Tamino overcomes a series of trials with the help of the title woodwind. For ten points, name this composer of<em> The Abduction From The Seraglio</em> and<em> The Magic Flute</em>.", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus<b> Mozart</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {"question": "One of these objects was taken by Vladimir Putin from Robert Kraft, who has earned four of them as an owner. The 1972 design symbolically includes 17 diamonds, and their designs often include gems and diamonds in the shapes of Roman numerals and the Vince Lombardi trophy. Tom Brady of the New England Patriots has four of, for ten points, what type of personal jewelry given to players and staff of teams who win the NFL championship?", "answer": "<b> Super Bowl ring</b> (prompt on ring or Super Bowl trophy, prize, etc.; do not accept Vince Lombardi trophy)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "One play depicting this event shows Giles Corey being executed with stones. Thomas Danforth and John Hathorne were heavily involved in this event, which was caused by the fits of Abigail Williams and Betty Parris, who were supposedly under the spell of slave Tituba.<em> The Crucible</em> depicted, for ten points, what 1690s event in which a Massachusetts town executed people for supposedly practicing magic?", "answer": "<b> Salem Witch Trials</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Drama"}, {"question": "This family\u2019s crest pictures a red cow eating grass against a yellow background. One member of this family hosted an orgy in the Banquet of the Chestnuts. That man, the enemy of Girolamo Savonarola, had formed the League of Venice to oppose Charles VIII\u2019s invasion of Italy. That man\u2019s son had embarked on the Romagna campaign, and was the inspiration for Niccolo Machiavelli\u2019s The Prince. For ten points, name this Italian family whose members included Cesare and Pope Alexander VI.", "answer": "<b> Borgia</b> family", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A 1948 expiration date was set for a mandate for this region and a corresponding memorandum regarding Transjordan established by the League of Nations. Since the 1993 Oslo Accords, parts of this region have been governed by a namesake National Authority currently led by Mahmoud Abbas. For ten points, name this Middle Eastern region, home to a state that competes over claims on the West Bank and Gaza Strip, as well as a potential \u201ctwo-state\u201d solution, with Israel.", "answer": "<b> Palestine</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Its original source of fresh water, Collect Pond, was landfilled and became the site of the Five Points slum. This island\u2019s neighborhood of Battery Park City was built from land excavated from a Minoru Yamasaki-designed skyscraper project, and a low-lying area in the north of this island became a center of African-American culture. For ten points, what island in New York City is home to Harlem and the World Trade Center?", "answer": "<b> Manhattan</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "The patronage of Gushi Khan increased the power of the holders of this position. A delegate of one holder of this position was forced at gunpoint to ratify the Seventeen Point Agreement. Men who hold this position are thought to be incarnations of Avalokiteshvara. The current holder of this position, Tenzin Gyatso, currently lives in exile in India. For ten points, name this position, the spiritual leader of Tibetan Buddhism.", "answer": "<b> Dalai Lama</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "At least two governors of this state have publicly refused to return a Virginian Confederate flag won at the Battle of Gettysburg. One, the current governor, endured a state government shutdown in 2011; the other was former professional wrestler Jesse Ventura. For ten points, name this state where Mark Dayton of the Democratic-Farmer-Labor Party governs from St. Paul.", "answer": "<b> Minnesota</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This company\u2019s John Archbold was almost assassinated in 1915 at Cedar Cliffs by members of the IWW. One of this company\u2019s founders, Henry Flagler, is the namesake of the Florida east coast Railway. Muckraker Ida Tarbell wrote a history of this company, which was dissolved after it was found to be violating the Sherman Antitrust Act in 1911. For ten points, name this petroleum company that was created by John D. Rockefeller.", "answer": "<b> Standard Oil</b> Company", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man documents his experiences traveling in China in his collection \u201cIn Time of War: A Sonnet Sequence with a Verse Commentary.\u201d One poem by this author asks \u201cWho can reach the deaf?/Who can speak for the dumb?\u201d and begins in \u201cone of the dives/On Fifty-Second Street\u201d; that poem declares \u201cWe must love each other or die.\u201d \u201cFuneral Blues\u201d was written by, for ten points, what poet who memorialized the beginning of WWII in his poem \u201cSeptember 1, 1939?\u201d", "answer": "W(ystan) H(ugh)<b> Auden</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A radiator of this color can be seen in the lower left Edward Hopper\u2019s</b><em><b> Automat</b></em><b>, and a flag of this color flies atop of the mast of Bosch\u2019s</b><em><b> Ship of Fools</b></em><b>. Gauguin painted a symbolic</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Christ of this color, which joins black, red, and blue as the only colors in most (*)</b> Piet Mondrian [PEET MOHN-dree-AHN] works. For ten points, name this primary color featured in Van Gogh\u2019s<em> Sunflowers</em>.", "answer": "<b> yellow</b> (accept<b> gold</b> or<b> bronze</b> before \u201cBosch\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, what dormant, snow-capped volcano in Tanzania is the highest point in Africa?", "answer": "Mount<b> Kilimanjaro</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>According to William of Poitiers, Pope Alexander II gave a papal banner to one leader prior to this battle. That leader led an attacking force landed in Pevensey, even though they</b> <b>intended to land in the (+)</b> <b>Isle of Wight. The other side in this battle had a defensive</b> <b>position on Senlac Hill, where one losing leader was shot in the (*)</b> eye. This battle is depicted on the Bayeux Tapestry, which shows the death of Harold Godwinson. For ten points, name this 1066 victory for William the Conqueror, who afterward would establish Norman rule of England.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hastings</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this longtime dictator of Cuba.", "answer": "Fidel<b> Castro</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Ben Shahn created a painting depicting these people in coffins titled for their Passion. Mario Buda probably assisted in the Wall Street (+) bombing two days after the indictment of these men, who were defended by Fred Moore for the (*) </b> murder of Alessandro Berardelli during a Massachusetts robbery in 1920. For ten points, name these two Italian anarchists whose death sentences were criticized worldwide as being politically motivated.", "answer": "Nicola<b> Sacco</b> and Bartolomeo<b> Vanzetti</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) <b>In response to this event, Mossad launched Operation Wraith of God and</b> <b>Operation Spring of Youth. This event\u2019s perpetrators demanded the release of</b> <b>Andreas Baader and (+)</b> <b>Ulrike Meinhoff, the founders of the Red Army Faction,</b> <b>and it was codenamed Operation Iqrit and Biram after villages depopulated by the</b> <b>(*)</b> Haganah. For ten points, name this event that saw members of Black September kill 11 Israeli coaches and athletes at the 1972 Summer Olympics in a certain German city. ANSWER:<b> Munich Massacre</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}